uh welcome back to
class and uh we're going to do some more
of the lumm okay and here we
go uh we are at chuk you guys p h y u
GS okay
good it's completely empty oh okay
good uh we're don't forget we're in the
middle of the Perfection of giving
and when we reach the end of the
Perfection of Joyful effort in Koto we
will be done with 14 years of work okay
yay
uh so Chu J they're talking about uh
kinds of
giving that
are I don't know this going okay kinds
of giving that are not good there kinds
of giving that are not good like you
can't give alcohol to a alcoholic or
things like that okay here's an example
chuki chuk means here uh
cow uh chin is the old word for
sacrifice and there was a Hindu custom
to kill a cow and sacrifice on the fire
and so that kind of giving he says t
means uh wrong wrong idea bad idea okay
and there's many stories of uh people
who made the cow offering who ended up
as the next
cow okay uh let me get this for you okay
good okay good uh then he has a list of
bad attitudes okay and uh when you're
giving when you're trying to do a good
thing your mind has to be in a good mood
okay so even you give some money or
something like that to the road project
for
example uh you have to avoid certain
kinds of attitudes okay they make the
giving strange okay N means uh you give
but you're kind of
grumpy okay number one number two Dru
means uh I'm going to give a little bit
more than that other
country our our stup is going to be a
little bit bigger you know like that
okay that's called competitive giving
okay uh kangam means uh I hope everybody
finds out that I gave the most money and
you know everyone will be impressed with
me
Dr jock means KY in Sanskrit what's
that famous yeah I hope everybody hears
about what a great Giver I am okay uh
shumba means uh little bit depressed
okay so you should be in a bright mood
when you give you should be happy okay
you shouldn't be like ah you know I hope
they stop this fundraising and start the
class again the fundraising is the class
you
understand okay uh gim
gam uh is very very very
important and it
means you know sunam was talking she got
everybody excited she got the countes
competing with each other I got excited
I offered too
much and now I'm stuck you know now I
have to give it and so give means I'm
sorry I got excited and I gave too much
okay so
it happens okay when you're in the
giving
business sometimes you get too excited
and you promise too much or you you know
you say I'll build a cabin or something
and then later you're like oh my God
what was I thinking you know so that's
very important not to regret okay just
shut up and give it okay and don't don't
uh in English we say second guess
yourself don't say oh maybe I did the
wrong thing or maybe I did the right
thing just shut up do it be happy next
time control
yourself okay all right okay CH Chi so
CH means uh I will help my friends but I
won't help other people and you see that
kind of thing okay so CH means uh bias
or you you you you help you help the
people you like and you don't help other
people I I have a personal thing that I
like my
country every 10 years they decide they
hate another country you know every by
the way when you're 71 you notice it you
figure it out you know and the enemy
changes every 10 years then the they go
they go to a different country say these
are the bad people they say Oh I thought
they were the bad people no no no
they're good people then this year these
are the bad people and these are the
enemy of my country this year and then
next year it always changes listen when
you're
71 it just changes every year every five
years you know so every time people in
my country say this people Arab people
are bad German people are bad Russian
people are bad you know other people are
bad every time I hear this I I try to go
to that
country uh so like I went to Morocco
and I did a two Monon retreat in a in a
village and I studied
Quran uh with the Imam and uh they were
from the Taliban these are the big enemy
of United States and uh we were all
friends and they're all nice people and
we had a sweet time and I learned Arabic
and I forgot Arabic and there's a joke
in the monastery I learn I forgot more
than you will ever
learn uh so
it just go You Know The Enemy changes
every couple years just don't believe it
okay just forget it whatever they tell
you just forget it make friends with
everybody and everybody's the same and
everybody wants to be friends with you
and just make friends with everybody and
it's so nice to be able to say I'm
friends with everybody in the world I
love every country you know people ask
me what's your country I said when I
lived in New York
and I was visiting these Muslim
countries you know they were bombing
things and I was like they say where you
from I say I'm from Manhattan and they
say what's Manhattan I say it's an
island off the coast of the United
States
so you know come on just everybody's
fine you get used to it when you travel
a lot you find out people are the same
everywhere people people are sweet
everywhere if you're sweet to them
people are sweet to you
okay Mara Mara means don't let your
giving be polluted by these like bias
okay things like that all right now uh
next picture you guys I think it's uh
tennis Shue yeah this is the funniest
thing I when I heard about it I was like
oh my
gosh uh people buy white tennis
shoes and then they try to keep them
white and I thought it seems so crazy to
me you know so they buy white tennis
then they spray them white every morning
they spray their tennis like you know I
don't even have time to find my shoes
then they have time to spray them you
know and
uh so this is an interesting idea as he
finishes this section on the Prof
section of
giving he has a very beautiful section
and I think it would make a whole nice
teaching at diamond mountain or
something I don't know he's quoting
shika
Samaya which is Shanti dea's other
famous book that nobody knows about okay
so Shanti Deva wrote two great books uh
and one is called shik so we know the
guide to the bodis saa's way of life
bodh
aatar but he wrote another book called
shika Samaya which means that he
collected together all the great advices
from the ancient sutras okay and
uh I've always wanted to teach it
because I thought wow the guide to the
bod saus way of life is so
amazing that the shiker suu Chaya must
be like a secret rock and roll hit you
know and uh so I actually worked on it
and then I decided there's a reason why
it's not
famous it's kind of dull actually I hate
to say that I shouldn't say that anyway
it's it's not him writing he just
collected quotations uh from different
books and it's kind of you know it's not
like the his other book his other book
is a great great classic it's one of the
greatest books ever
written but the sh is a little bit it's
just a kind of a big collection of
quotations and it's long uh so I I ended
up not working on it uh but he quotes it
here and he says look there's something
else about giving that you have to know
and it's very beautiful okay it's that
all the stuff you own
now and and your
body and all your possessions and your
time uh once you become a bodh Safa
those are already
sold okay all right your
body
your white
shoes your house your money you know
your time which to me is much more
precious than things uh everything you
own
as a bodh SAA you have already promised
to give it okay so now it's not yours
anymore you're just taking care of it
until you can finish the giving see what
I mean everything you
own was already dedicated to other
people okay and your time and your
body uh chendur uh you have offered it
as a you offered to be the
servant of every living being therefore
you don't own it anymore okay you you're
caretaker you are temporarily keeping it
until the delivery date you see what I
mean you're like the Amazon Storehouse
Warehouse okay you don't own those
things in the Amazon warehouse they just
haven't been shipped yet
okay so your body your money your time
as a bodh Safa when you took your bodh
Safa
vows you already committed to give those
to other people you're just taking care
of them until the day comes and they say
Okay Shipman now SH now
deliver okay now I want your money or
now I want your house or now I want your
time okay now and the sh DEA
says while the stuff is still in the
warehouse you have a responsibility to
take good care of it okay it's not yours
anymore okay once you took your bodh off
of
vows all your money all your stuff all
your time and your body were already
given away it just hasn't been delivered
yet so you cannot mess up your body
before the delivery okay you you it's
not yours anymore it belongs to other
people you have to stay
healthy you have to stay healthy that's
that's your responsibility because it's
not your body anymore I think it's a
beautiful idea okay like if you say G
when you when you overeat your shirt is
all my wife says my belly
button I don't know the shirt open opens
up
here you know some guys like Juan their
shirt opens up
here you know my opens up here you know
and my wife says your belly button
showing I'm
like you know
and so you you can't gain weight because
it will make you sick okay you cannot
gain weight you have to take care of
your body you have to go to the gym uh
you have to do your yoga you know you
have to eat
wisely because it's not your body
anymore it doesn't belong to you you are
temporary caretaker you are taking care
of it in the in the warehouse until the
shipment date and I I think it's a
beautiful beautiful argument and it's
that's how he ends the first Perfection
okay he quotes Shanti DEA and he says
you don't have the right to be
overweight you don't have the right not
to sleep you don't have the right not to
take care of yourself you don't own that
body anymore you promised already to
give it away okay which means you should
join the good night book
club they have a
slide if you want to irritate the tech
staff keep asking for stuff you didn't
ask for
uh they figure it out uh again I think
the good night book club is one of the
best ideas we ever
had uh you
promise at 10:00 to you know here I do 9
o' and 5:00 but at home I do 10:00 Rob
comes to my house and he takes away my
computer and my phone and I look for it
I wake up at 2 o'cl I'm like walking
around the
house where's my computer you know
where's my phone I've got to look up
what's the average temperature in ear UT
you know and then I'm like maybe it
doesn't
matter and no do you ever get I mean
when you join the book club you're gonna
find some you're gonna find out how
weird your information hunger got you
know like I wonder if fingernails grow
faster or toenails grow faster you know
and no and you ask I look it up you know
and uh
so it's called the good night book club
you 10
o00 get rid of your uh electronics and
stuff we have a special if you're living
on your own or something like I I give
with my wife's home she sometimes she
has another house she has to take care
of it but when she's home I put it on
her side of the bed so I kind of have to
crawl over her to get to it and she then
she hits me you know it doesn't matter
which fingernail grow faster you know
and uh if she's not there I give it Rob
comes and picks it up
okay there's a joke about the good night
but then you get one of these books
these paper books you get one of these
paper books and you you you order it
okay the mixed nuts translations keep
one by your bedside okay uh at
10:00 open up the good you know the
mixed nuts book I swear you will be
asleep in 2 minutes okay it's so
difficult and so deep it's great for
sleeping by the way if you want my
personal favorite it's majika okay uh it
puts me to sleep in two minutes okay so
read get a paper book Put it night next
to your bed at
10:00 uh put away your computer give it
put it somewhere where you cannot get to
it because you will you will figure out
a way if you're staying in a hotel room
you have to add the TV controller okay I
don't have a TV at home but I but when
I'm traveling I have this yeah here we
go please sign up okay it's the best
thing I can teach you okay I taught for
100 years I taught I have two and a half
million files on my
computer uh I taught my whole life but
this is the best thing okay uh you you
will sleep well you'll be happy you'll
be creative you won't do bad things at
night okay and and I never slept eight
hours in my whole life and now I sleep
eight hours like a baby you know and 10
o'clock I'm like
d 6 o'clock I'm like
Ding and uh
I can work I I I start work at
6:05 I don't allow uh any meetings and
stuff uh until 11: so I work for five
hours and uh it's wonderful it's really
really wonderful so if you you know you
came here for me to teach you something
that's the best thing I can teach you
okay join the good night book club okay
what's the short name name good night
club good nightclub what's the short
short name the nightclub
okay probably in your dreams Ben will be
playing Jimmy
Hendry uh that's a nightclub okay but
that's the best thing I can give you
okay uh don't just don't wait till
you're 70 to do it okay it's stupid okay
do it now and you will be more
productive and your mind will be clear
and happy okay really okay and your
meditation would be awesome okay read a
book when you fall asleep when you get
up meditate uh on on that five minutes
10 minutes and your life will change
your whole life will change okay if you
came here to learn
something good night book club all right
now here's Shanti dea's advice for
taking care of your the stuff you have
not delivered yet to living beings okay
here's the advice it has three or four
parts
okay it's it's four parts in three
groups so it's 12 but you don't have to
worry about it okay here it is number
one you already committed your body to
other people you promised already if you
took bod of
V somewhere in there you said I am the
servant
of That's The Vow
I promise to be a servant of all people
I give my body so it's not your body
anymore okay don't take Bud SAA vows for
fun it's a big commitment okay then all
your stuff goes to the Amazon
warehouse okay
Shen first of all keep reminding
yourself that you already committed your
stuff to other other people
okay you already
committed and here's the important
partu means until the time is ready for
delivery
G it's your
responsibility to take care of your body
and don't let it get hurt don't feed it
too much don't work it too hard you know
don't not
exercise okay don't not do your yoga
okay it's not your body anymore you you
already promised it to somebody else
therefore you have to take care of it I
don't know about you I have
trouble taking care of
myself for selfish reasons you see what
I mean I'm not a good person but I have
trouble if my wife says you got to take
care of yourself you know you have to
eat
vegetables you know you have to eat
vegetables uh you know otherwise you
you're going to hurt yourself and I'm
like yeah okay I do lots of stuff that
hurts me I'm it doesn't impress me but
if she says look you're you're hurting
other people's property that doesn't
belong to you anymore that belongs to
somebody else then I'm like wow that's
bad you know I got it's not mine it's
like borrowing something from it's like
borrowing somebody's car and smashing it
right Stanley by the way he
didn't wait wait he didn't do it he had
it done to him okay uh and the car's
still in the hospital I think yeah after
two months uh okay so you don't want to
hurt other people's stuff you can hurt
your own stuff okay let's say so gelen
gelen means things that would hurt your
body too much sugar too much coffee not
enough
sleep uh you know too to crazy busy busy
is good crazy busy is also good but
crazy crazy busy is not good okay uh L
su su means protect your body you it's
your
responsibility to take good care of
yourself okay because you already you
have to live a long life okay it's it
takes so many millions of years to get
here it takes so many millions of years
to get to this room
and you have to take care of that person
okay that person is very valuable I
don't care if you think you're valuable
or not you are okay you are one in you
are one in 10 million okay and you think
you're a normal person you're not if
you're in this
room uh millions of years of hard work
went into you and uh don't waste it
don't don't hurt it don't you have to
you have a
responsibility to sleep yourself away
well to eat yourself well to not
overwork yourself well okay play rock
and roll once in a
while by the way that's a definitely
people are like oh guess I play rock and
roll you know and I'm like yeah I play
rock and roll you
know uh you gotta you gotta relax you
got to have fun fun is one of the four
kinds of sustenance I think okay you got
to have fun people say gu you said you
didn't have time to meet me and you're
playing rock and
roll I'm like I gotta have some fun you
know or I can't meet anybody you know
okay all right uh Mig mwa means uh TBA
DBA means Purity don't don't let your
body do bad things okay don't let your
body hurt other people cheat other
people okay don't uh
and what he means is keep spraying your
tennis
shoes okay keep spraying your tennis
shoes it's you gave away those tennis
shoes
already so if they get a little dirty
you have to spray them again okay your
that's your body and that's your time
okay you have to take good care of it if
you hurt it if you do something to hurt
yourself you have to take care of
yourself you know when you get to my age
frankly you have to go to doctors all
the time and I don't like it and I I've
never did it in my whole life I never
would I didn't have a doctor for many
many years when you get to a certain age
you have to you have to take care of
yourself you have to find good doctors
and you have to keep your doctor
appointments and stuff like that okay
and let them cut you up when they want
to and stuff and uh you because you have
to take you have to try to live as long
as you can okay all right uh
give it be ready to give it away take
good care of it do not make it dirty for
the next person okay keep it pure keep
your heart pure keep your body healthy
for the next person who's going to use
it
okay then he talks about
um taking care of your body in the
future you also have this responsibility
okay next
life that now it's getting serious right
gu I have enough trouble taking care of
the body I was born with now you want me
to take care of the body I haven't been
born with yet and the answer is
yes okay you have a future
responsibility your future body has
already been
sold okay it already went to the Amazon
Karma
warehouse and uh you have to you have a
resp
responsibility to collect the karma that
will give you a good body next time okay
because that one was so got it so not
only you have to take care of the body
you were born in because it's not yours
anymore your future bodies are already
committed they're already sold they
haven't been delivered yet okay so you
have a
responsibility to collect the karma to
create a good body next time cool got it
it's very fun game I think it's like all
right you know I'll try to be
generous because I promised my body next
life and I wanted to have enough money
you know or like that okay I'm going to
take care of hungry
people I'm going to take care of
homeless people I'm going to help people
whose countries are at War
or because I want my next body to be a
nice one uh because I promised it
already Okay it's like you promised a
gift to your grandchild or something you
know I promise you a good birthday
present next year then you have to start
collecting the money and stuff right
okay depends on how expensive your
granddaughter is okay uh so he says be
ready to give
protect your body and keep it in good
shape okay also your future body then he
has uh in the L
Rim he mentions eight eight future
things about your body that you should
get ready okay there's eight eight
qualities of your future body that you
should start preparing now okay you you
have to give away a nice body in your
next line which means what can you do
now collect the seeds to make sure you
have a good body in your next life okay
and here's the and by the way it's so
fun to think like this right uh it's so
nice that it's not selfish it's like you
have to take care of your body you have
to make sure you have enough money in
the future you know and it's just kind
of to me it's boring I I don't do it I
don't like to do it but if you say you
need to take care of your next body
because you're going to give it away and
you can't give away lousy stuff you got
to give away good quality stuff
so if you say if you put it that way to
me I get excited about my next life body
I'm like oh yeah let's okay tell me what
to do G okay there's eight
things and it's not in the L Rim it's uh
it's by Shanti DEA and and the writer of
the Lum RM he says go go find it in
Shanti DEA and I guess he knew that we
would have
Al uh to find it okay so I went and
found it in the database okay and here's
the eight okay it's not in the Lo room
number one
uh protect life help sick people in this
life so that that future body will have
a long life okay so the first one is
collect the
causes that your future body will have a
what do you call it when you buy a new
car a lot of
mileage okay you don't want to buy a new
car and and it's going to break down
after 100 miles you want a you want a
400,000 mile car next time okay so
collect the causes for a 400,000 mile
body next time and that's helping sick
people okay help helps s people number
one uh number two be
patient don't get angry okay then you're
like what's that got to do with my next
life body we want it to be
attractive okay we want it to be
attractive it's not
selfish it's not what do you call it uh
conceited it's practical okay if you
look nice more people will come to your
class Etc okay
seriously and that's an old Buddhist
Atia said I'm so glad I was born
handsome uh cuz all the Tibetans come to
my class you know and no he he said it's
a it's a Karma you should prepare for
your next body and that means don't get
angry okay don't get angry in this way
you know you really piss me off but I'm
not going to get pissed off because I
have to teach in my next life okay you
got to think like that okay you deserve
me to flip a bird of you the way you're
driving you deserve to have me flip a
bird of you uh but I'm not going to do
it because I already committed the next
body and I have to make sure it's pretty
handsome or beautiful okay like that
okay uh rtoa means
uh you
know be
generous so that in your next life
you're born into a a country that has
money okay you're born into a country
that has money and it's
helpful okay it's helpful if you're born
into a super poor
country uh you don't have the resources
to help people okay and and I'm not
saying you're a bad person you're you're
fine you're okay but like the person who
built the roads here and who built he
also built the the Student Center that's
that's a good
rebirth you know you guys need roads yes
all right oh you need a new car on the
new road yeah he bought a new car he
said do you guys have new cars no okay
let's throw in a new car you know let's
get you a new truck also you know and
and I remember when he commit you
know we me and shopping we fund raised I
think it was
$200,000 and it was a big deal and and
he said okay I promise $2 200,000 then
we went back we used up to 200,000 yes
and there's no windows doors or floor
and he's like all right here's another
200,000 it was a million it went to a
million it went five times over uh
that's why it's so
beautiful uh but uh be be generous okay
be generous set up a good set set up a
good body for the next life that has
some money that lives in a country that
has money you know and then you can help
more people are you a bad person if you
don't have money I didn't say
that should you should you quit your
Retreats and go try to make more money
so you can give away more money I didn't
say that either
uh give away as much as you can is the
same thing okay give away what you can
it's the same thing if you have $10 and
you give away
eight you'll have the same result as
this guy who built the Student Center
okay if you give away what you can
everything that you can without hurting
your family without hurting
yourself uh you know have be comfortable
have a nice house have a nice food have
a nice car blah blah and then give away
as much as you can uh you're fine that's
fine okay Wu chwa wuk chwa means
uh share power okay whatever power you
have share it with other people okay if
you're the boss of diamond mountain or
you're the boss of the all publicity
blah blah
blah then
uh share share your power with other
people okay what responsibility you have
what position you have share it be
generous with your power be generous uh
let other people
share you know in the responsibilities
and if they want to give them a chance
to to to do fun things give them a
chance to be the boss if you're a boss
the best way to be a boss is to let
other people share the boss boss stuff
okay and then you'll be boss Forever by
the way okay so
share share the authority share share
what position you have don't be greedy
share it and then in your next life you
will have authority you you will be in
charge of stuff and then you can do good
stuff okay all right uh number five s
tumba say s
tumba uh keep your
promises okay keep your promises when
you say something stick to it okay uh
keep your promises okay don't forget
your promise I think keeping your
promise is 50% remembering your promise
okay you know so try to when you promise
something kind of keep a mental record
okay I promised that so I have to do
that okay keep keep a mental record or
keep a on your
phone uh a list of things that you
promised and then keep your word
okay s Zumba means keep your promises
okay when you don't promise
easily but when you promise keep it okay
and keep it no matter what keep it okay
uh and then in your next life people
will always believe you and and people
will listen to you okay it's so nice to
collect the karma that people say okay
gesla I'm on it you know and it took me
a long time to figure out the the karma
and it took me a long time to collect
the karma but I have to say it's fun you
know yesterday like 12 people are like G
said I had to do that so I had to do it
I'm like
yeah okay so you know uh keep your word
all right
uh number six
right yeah uh you want to have a good
reputation in your next life okay and
that means
uh take care not to BlahBlah about other
people's problems or other people's
faults okay don't waste your
time talking to other people about other
people okay don't waste your time okay
everybody everybody has problems we all
have problems we all have bad habits
everybody okay if someone's in this
world is pretending that they don't have
a bad habit they are just pretending
that they don't have a bad habit because
you don't get to come to this world
unless you have bad habits okay so
somebody in this world says Gua I'm as
pure as a snow you know I'm like no
you're not and they say why not and I
say cause you're here goddamn you know
if you're here this is where they put
the bad
kids this is the back of the class you
know this world is okay we all the same
okay we all have the same problems okay
so don't waste your time making lists in
your mind of the bad habits of other
people you know pay attention to you you
got plenty to work on you don't need
extra okay and then if you work on your
own bad
habits you are preparing a nice body for
next time and and that body will have
authority and fame they will be famous
and it's you can use Fame you can misuse
Fame you know you can be Addicted to
Fame you can uh hurt yourself trying to
be famous but if you are famous you can
use it uh if you know how to use it it's
helpful okay all right number what
[Music]
seven each country has its own uh social
levels you know I and every country is
different you know in you know there's
countries where uh in the universe okay
not this
world uh if you're left ear is bigger
than your right ear you're high C you're
high society you know you know you're a
high person you know oh look what she's
so beautiful why her left ear is twice
as big as her right ear you know there's
no you laugh there's worlds like that
you know there's worlds like that we
have our own weird stuff you know I
don't know his nose is you know so short
or so long you know it must be a good
person you know so uh there's this thing
that your next life to be born into the
big left ear and small right ear okay or
whatever is popular on that
planet okay okay so you got to be ready
I I have a vision of the next one myself
I I I kind of designed it and I kind of
looked at it I looked ahead I have a I
have a person I'm going to be and uh I I
I
uh they should be a person who's
respected in their society you see what
I mean that's what I'm trying to say and
every society is different okay in some
societies if you talk a lot you're
respected in some societies if you don't
talk you're respected okay so it doesn't
matter it it every country has different
Customs okay but try to set up the karma
to be born into the best one next life
and Everyone likes it oh he's so
handsome
why his left here so big you know and
then you know try to set up the karma
for that okay it's all silly but it
matters okay last one
eight uh set up the karma to to have a
super healthy body we said long life was
number one but number eight is that body
should have a lot of Vitality that body
should be healthy okay it's you can live
a long unhealthy life right so long life
is not enough you want a body which
is you can push it okay it's healthy
it's a healthy body you can get up early
you can you can build temples you can
build stupas you know then you can go
study for8 hours you know you want a
body that has energy okay so okay
what's for $100 everybody's
like what's the nickname for setting up
the karma for these
eight what's the nickname for setting up
the karma for this eight for
$100 raise your
hand joyful effort no no
okay wait the person with the Box
decides who gets the
money to be
Joe what Jo Joe nice nice answer but I'm
not taking it Sam Jong Sam Jong what she
say oh
no come on this easy by the way if I get
three or four bad answers I can of the B
four steps oh okay one more
try renunciation forget
it show that picture the last
one paint your
shoes paint your shoes okay don't forget
the the picture okay the picture is take
care of your body
in this life and take care of your body
in your next life take care of those
shoes be one of those stupid people who
sprays their white shoes every
morning because they are not your shoes
anymore they they belong to other people
okay you have to take good care of the
body you were born with and you have to
take care of the body you don't have yet
that's your responsibility okay I don't
know life got more complicated right
Ella
okay yeah I like it I think it's again I
have trouble taking care of myself for
myself but if you tell me I have to take
care of myself for other people I I then
I
respond my boss used to take me into the
in the New York in the big Corporation
he used to call me and said uh we got a
big order we got to ship 10,000 Rings
tomorrow to JC peny you know you got to
work over time you cannot go home to
your llama and take your lrim class you
got to stay here with me you know and
I'm like I'm leaving and and he's like
I'll fire you and I'm like fire me
that's okay I'm not g to miss my class
you know he's like okay get out of here
you know and then like 6 months later
he's like Mike it's they always call you
at 4
59 right one minute before the company
closed he's like he's like come to my
office I'm like what he says
mike you're the only
one you're the without you we're nothing
you
know we we can't get we can't do
anything when you're here we are we know
what to do when you're not here we fall
apart you know you got to help us
you know we got a big shipment tomorrow
you know please you know you're the best
I'm like
yeah okay all right if you tell me it's
for somebody else I respond I feel like
okay I can do that I I'll eat my
vegetables if it's for one of my
students you know if it's for my future
students I'll eat my vegetables if it's
from me I'm like a you know last night
we had great enchiladas from a certain
group from
Mexico and someone tried to sneak in
some
spinach
and my
cat she will eat the red food and she
will leave the dry food so I eat all the
enchiladas and uh spinach I gave to
andriana and okay but if you tell me
gesla for for the sake of others you
have to Eat Your Spinach I'm like okay
I'm on it you know okay it's I think
every one of us is like that if it's for
someone else you can do it okay all
right uh he covered your
body what time do I
stop 15 minutes okay he covered your do
do I have to stop earlier because you
have to do 10,000 thank yous or
something or you going to make
me when do the thank you
start okay let's say five more minutes
okay we'll finish this point because
then we're going on to the next
Perfection okay let's finish this
Perfection okay first Perfection then he
says uh the same thing applies to your
possessions the first one was for your
body okay you have to take care of your
body for others and then you have to
take care of your future body for others
now you have to take care of all your
stuff okay like your car that's an
interesting idea okay you have to take
good care of your
car because it's not yours anymore
you're borrowing it okay when you drive
your car you are driving a car which you
already gave away to other people they
just didn't accept delivery yet they
didn't take it yet it's not your car
anymore therefore you have to take good
care of your stuff I don't like to take
care of stuff you know I really don't
like to take care of things you know I I
hate taking the car for the 5,000 mile
maintenance stuff I hate it I never do
it but if you put a guilt trip on me we
can't do it without you Mike you know
you're the special one you know I'm like
you're right you know uh somebody has to
take care of the car you know you know
why because you might have to drive
another person to the hospital or
something you have you have
responsibility to take good care of your
stuff because you might need it to serve
other people because it's not your stuff
anymore cool you got to take good care
of your house okay by the
way keep your house clean of junk okay
because when you die someone else is
going to have to clean it out and that's
so
irritating you know you you your friend
dies and you go to their house he like
oh my God there's six days of work here
you know keep your house
clean don't collect too much
crap okay keep your house clean keep
your life light you know keep keep your
house pretend you're going to die
tomorrow and don't let other people
clean up your junk okay get rid of the
junk now okay by the way
I do this like I don't know once a year
I take all the junk and I put it out for
the garbage truck you know then I go to
bed at
10:00 10:30 I wake up I go outside I
take half the stuff back you know I'm
like maybe I need these shoes my wife's
like you didn't wear those shoes for six
years I'm saying but you never know you
know okay so get rid of all your extra
stuff don't don't make someone else
clean clean up your stuff after you die
and you don't know when you're going to
die so you might as well clean it out
now okay let your house be clean like a
Zen
temple okay same steps uh be ready to
give your
possessions uh try
to increase your generosity mentally in
your
meditations uh protect your possessions
the stuff you own somebody else might
have to use it next week There's a joke
that your clothes will go looking for a
new
person okay when you die you know
they'll give them to the in America we
give them to the used clothing shop and
okay so take good care of them uh TPA
means uh make sure your possessions were
acquired
honestly uh don't keep stuff in your
house that you acquired by stealing or
by cheating people or something like
that when your possessions should be
clean your possessions should be
karmically clean okay uh because because
you cannot deliver to other people
possessions which are not comically
clean okay so don't it's an interesting
idea don't cheat people to get stuff
because when you die and that stuff is
offered to other people
it'll be dirty okay it'll be dirty don't
don't don't pass on dirty stuff to other
people all the stuff you own should be
clean you got it by by Clean ways and
you got it by sweet ways and you did
nothing you own was was nothing you own
was acquired by cheating anybody or
stealing it or anything like that okay
that's not appropriate to keep in your
house that we should teach this to Marie
condo it's like Karma
cleanliness Karma tidiness yeah
everything should be karmically tidy
that'd be interesting wouldn't it uh a
joint program yeah uh that'd be very
interesting
CH yeah and don't forget to pile up lots
of cool stuff in your next life okay so
you know be generous in this life but
the motivation is next life I'll have
really cool stuff to give to people you
know I can finally get a Tesla in my
next life you know and then I'll give it
away you know something cool to give
away to people uh okay last one and then
we'll do the 9,000 thank you
um now so he said body and then he said
possessions and now he says you have to
do this
same steps with your good
seeds very interesting very interesting
okay you have to be you every time you
meditate at the end of The Meditation
practice giving away the good seeds like
we did today okay on the sunlight okay
can you give away good seeds
no is it good to pretend you're giving
me good seeds yes okay uh can you teach
other people to make their own good
seeds and give away good seeds that way
yes okay so be then he says don't get
control yeah who
said 100
bucks okay there's uh two kinds of
answers
right one is an answer where I bet $100
and you answer
it then one is where I didn't bet $100
but the answer is so good it should get
$100 okay yeah
uh so what's anger got to do with this
subject
$100 raise your hand what's anger have
to do with this exact subject we've been
talking
about hello anger destroys all the good
seats okay
then there's no good to dedicate to the
next life good
$100 your good seeds also don't belong
to you
anymore oh my God gu this this is
getting too serious I don't mind to give
up my
car but my good students yeah you're a
bu sapper you promised to give away
everything you have includes your good
seeds your good seeds in your own mind
don't belong to you anymore they belong
to other people you have a
moral
responsibility not to hurt
what the good seeds in your own mind
what's the best way to destroy the good
seeds in your own mind anger you have to
as a bodh
SAA you have to avoid anger
because those seeds you will destroy
don't belong to you it's like it's like
smashing somebody else's car okay it's
not yours anymore okay you don't have
the right to get angry because you don't
have the right to destroy the good
thingss in your own mind because you
gave them away already okay wow this is
getting hard
uh okay I'm almost finished
yeah he just says
uh last thing
[Music]
okay it's also your moral
responsibility not just to protect the
good seeds you have but to multiply them
okay it's your moral responsibility if
if you're holding money for somebody
else that you already gave to somebody
else but you didn't deliver the money
yet it's your responsibility to invest
it and make some interest and deliver
more money got it okay if you're holding
money for so I'm holding $10,000 for the
Latin America
Tour
uh in the toilet uh me
and me and my friends decided I should
deliver it
today okay and
uh but I should I should try to make
some interest on it before I deliver it
you see right Aldo like I should deliver
11 or something right uh so it's your
moral
responsibility to deliver more than you
committed okay uh so you have to make
interest on your good seat so now for
$100 and then I'm going to shut up and
I'll go sit down and I'll listen to the
thank you uh except that we got to do
this thing right okay uh last thing
how are you going to make interest on
your mental seeds before you give them
away $100 you have to raise your hand
you have to speak into the orange the
the money comes out of The Orange
Box by the way the next next Retreat
when you come try to be the Box
holder then you can make a deal for 50%
okay
what
okay bring a fake box oh no I'll give
two I'll give two if the answer is
correct I'll give two I don't mind
purify my mind my body everything wait
I'll rephrase the question I got mental
seeds in my in my mind good seeds Okay
I'm
gonna they don't I don't own them
anymore like everything else I have they
already been dedic at to other people
I'm just holding
them and I could deliver interest on
them you know instead of giving $10,000
for the tour I could give $111,000 if I
invest them
wisely how do you
get 100 good mental seats to turn into
110 good mental seats
easily wait
wait C
meditation Mike wait Mike Mike what was
your answer rejoicing coffee meditation
yeah
$100 he got $100
second second hund I'm going to knock
okay deliver more seeds than you
promised that's always good when you
when you by the way people ask me for
business advice borrow when you borrow
money for your business at 10% right you
borrow 100,000 you promise 110,000 back
give
120 and you will be so
popular and you'll make so much you know
people will loan your money like crazy
get always give back more than you
promised okay got it also with your own
mental steds all right